When I've
been building applications with
large language models, I don't think
I've ever come to the prompt that
I ended up using in the final application
on my first attempt.
And this isn't what matters. As
long as you have a good process
to iteratively make your
prompt better, then you'll
be able to come
to something that works
well for the task
you want to achieve.
You may have heard me say that when
I train a machine learning model,
it almost never works the first time.
In fact, I'm
very surprised that the first
model I trained works. I
think we're prompting, the odds
of it working the
first time is maybe
a little bit higher, but as
he's saying, doesn't matter if the
first prompt works, what matters most is
the process for getting to prompts
that works for your application. So
with that, let's jump into the
code and let me show
you some frameworks to
think about how to
iteratively develop a prompt.
All right. So, if you've
taken a machine learning class
with me before, you
may have seen me use
a diagram saying that with machine
learning development, you often have an
idea and
then implement it. So,
write the code, get the data,
train your model, and that gives
you an experimental result. And you
can then look at
that output, maybe do error analysis, figure out
where it's working or
not working, and then
maybe even change your idea
of exactly what problem
you want to solve
or how to approach
it. And then change implementation and run another
experiment and so
on, and iterate
over and over to get
to an effective machine learning model. If you're
not familiar with machine learning,
haven't seen
this diagram before, don't worry about
it. Not that important for the
rest of this presentation. But
when you are writing
prompts to develop an application
using an LLM, the
process can be quite
similar, where you have an
idea for what you want to
do, the task you want
to complete, and you can then
take a first attempt at writing
a prompt that hopefully
is clear and specific,
and maybe, if appropriate,
gives the system time
to think. And then
you can
run it and see what result
you get. And if it doesn't
work well enough the first time,
then the iterative process
of figuring out why the instructions, for
example, were not
clear enough, or why it didn't
give the algorithm
enough time to think,
allows you to refine
the idea, refine the
prompt, and so on,
and to go around this loop
multiple times until you end up
with a prompt that
works for your application.
This too is why
I personally have not
paid as much attention
to the internet articles
that say 30 perfect prompts,
because I think,
there probably isn't
a perfect prompt for
everything under the sun. It's more
important that you have
a process for developing
a good prompt for
your specific application.
So, let's
look at an example together in code. I
have here the starter
code that you saw
in the previous videos, have
import OpenAI, import OS. Here
we get the OpenAI API key, and
this is the same
helper function that you
saw as last time.
And I'm going to use as the
running example in this video, the
task of summarizing a fact
sheet for a chair. So, let
me just paste that in here.
And feel free to
pause the video and
read this more carefully
in the notebook on the left if you
want. But here's a fact sheet for a chair
with a description saying it's part
of a beautiful family of mid-century inspired, and
so on. It talks about
the construction, has the dimensions,
options for the
chair, materials, and so on.
It comes from Italy.
So, let's say you want to
take this fact sheet and help a marketing
team write a description
for an online retail
website.
Let me just quickly run these three,
and then we'll
come up with a prompt as follows, and
I'll just... and I'll just paste
this in.
So my prompt here says,
your task is to
help a marketing team
create the description for
a retail website with
a product based on
a techno fact sheet,
write a product description,
and so on. Right?
So this is my first
attempt to explain the task
to the large language model.
So let me hit shift-enter, and
this takes a few seconds to run,
and we get this result.
It looks like it's
done a nice job writing a description, introducing
a stunning mid-century inspired
office chair, perfect addition,
and so on. But when
I look at this, I go, boy, this is
really long. It's done a
nice job doing exactly what I
asked it to, which is start
from the technical fact
sheet and write a
product description.
But when I look at this, I go,
this is kind of long.
Maybe we want it to
be a little bit shorter. So,
I have had an idea,
I wrote a prompt, got a result. I'm
not that happy with it because it's too
long. So, I will
then clarify my prompt and say, use at
most 50 words to try to give better
guidance on the desired
length of this. And let's run it
again.
Okay. This actually looks like
a much nicer short
description of the product,
introducing a mid-century
inspired office chair, and
so on. Five of you just, yeah, both
stylish and practical. Not bad. And
let me double check the
length that this is. So, I'm going
to take the response, split it
according to where the
space is, and then, you know,
print out the length. So it's
52 words. It's actually not bad.
Large language models are
okay, but not that great
at following instructions about
a very precise word
count. But this is actually
not bad. Sometimes it will print
out something with 60
or 65 and so on words, but it's
kind of within reason.
Some of the things you
could try to do would
be, to say use at most
three sentences.
Let me run that again. But these are
different ways to tell the large
language model, what's
the length of the output that you want.
So this is 1, 2, 3, I
count three sentences, looks
like I did a pretty good job. And
then I've also seen people sometimes do
things like, I don't know, use
at most 280 characters. Large language models,
because of the
way they interpret text, using something called
a tokenizer, which I won't
talk about. But they tend to
be so-so at counting characters.
But let's see, 281 characters. It's actually
surprisingly close. Usually a
large language model is, doesn't get
it quite this close. But these are
different ways that you
can play with to try to control the
length of the output
that you get. But let me
just switch it back to use
at most 50 words.
And there's
that result that we had just now.
As we continue to refine
this text for our websites,
we might decide that, boy,
this website isn't
selling direct to consumers, is
actually intended to
sell furniture to
furniture retailers that
would be more interested in the
technical details of the chair and
the materials of the chair. In
that case, you
can take this prompt and say, I
want to modify this prompt to get it
to be more precise
about the technical details.
So let me keep on modifying this prompt.
And I'm going to say,
this description is
intended for furniture retailers,
so should be technical
and focus on materials,
products and constructed from,
well, let's run that.
And let's see.
Not bad, says, you know,
coated aluminum base
and pneumatic chair,
high-quality materials. So
by changing the prompt, you
can get it to focus
more on specific characters, on
specific characteristics you
wanted to.
And when I look at this,
I might decide at the end of the
description, I also wanted to
include the product ID.
So the two offerings of this chair,
SWC 110, SWC 100. So, maybe I can
further improve this prompt.
And to get it to
give me the product IDs,
I can add this instruction
at the end of the description,
include every 7-character
product ID in
the technical specification, and
let's run it,
and see what happens.
And so, it says,
introduce you to our
Miss Agents 5 office chair,
shell colors,
talks about plastic coating,
aluminum base, practical,
some options,
talks about the two product IDs. So,
this looks pretty good.
And what you've just seen is
a short example of the iterative
prompt development that
many developers will
go through.
And I think, a guideline is,
in the last video,
you saw Isa share a number of best
practices, and so,
what I usually do is keep
best practices like that in mind,
be clear and specific,
and if necessary,
give the model time to think.
With those in mind, it's
worthwhile to often take
a first attempt at
writing a prompt, see
what happens, and then go from there
to iteratively refine the
prompt to get closer
and closer to the
result that you need. And so, a
lot of the successful prompts that
you may see used in various
programs was arrived at at an
iterative process like this. Just
for fun, let me show you an
example of a even
more complex prompt that
might give you a sense of what chatGPT
can do, which is, I've just
added a few extra
instructions here. After the
description, include a
table that gives the
product dimensions, and then,
you know, format everything
as HTML. So, let's run that.
And in practice,
you end up with a prompt like this,
really only after multiple iterations.
I don't think I know anyone
that would write this
exact prompt the first
time they were trying
to get the system
to process a fact sheet.
And so,
this actually outputs a bunch of HTML.
Let's display the HTML to see
if this is even valid
HTML and see if this works. And
I don't actually know it's going to
work, but let's see. Oh, cool. All right. Looks
like it rendered.
So, it has this really
nice looking description of a
chair, construction, materials, product dimensions.
Oh, it looks like I left out the use
at most 50 words instruction,
so this is a little bit long,
but if you want that, you know,
you can even feel free to pause the
video, tell it to be more
succinct and regenerate this and
see what results you get.
So, I hope you take away from
this video that
prompt development is
an iterative process. Try something,
see how it does not yet,
fulfill exactly what you want,
and then think about
how to clarify your instructions,
or in some cases,
think about how to
give it more space to think to get
it closer to delivering
the results that you want.
And I think, the key to being
an effective prompt engineer isn't
so much about knowing
the perfect prompt, it's about
having a good process to develop
prompts that are
effective for your
application. And in
this video, I illustrated
developing a prompt using
just one example. For more
sophisticated applications, sometimes you
will have multiple
examples, say a
list of 10 or even 50
or 100 fact sheets, and iteratively
develop a prompt and
evaluate it against a
large set of cases.
But for the early
development of most applications,
I see many people developing it
sort of the way I am,
with just one example,
but then for more mature applications,
sometimes it could be useful to
evaluate prompts against
a larger set of examples,
such as to test
different prompts on dozens
of fact sheets to
see how is average
or worst case performances
on multiple fact sheets.
But usually, you end up doing
that only when an
application is more mature,
and you have to
have those metrics to
drive that incremental last
few steps of prompt improvement.
So with that, please do play with
the Jupyter Code notebook
examples and try out
different variations and see
what results you get. And when you're
done, let's go
on to the next video, where we'll talk about
one very common use of large
language models in software applications, which
is to
summarize text. So when you're
ready, let's go on to the
next video.